BALKIS CHACHIA

SOUSSE, TN | PHONE: +(216)55975375 | balkischachia12 @gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/balkis-chachia github.com/balkisch1

SUMMARY

I am a final-year software development student at ISET Sousse, with practical experience in the field, and system administration. I have a solid foundation in web development, specializing in Python, and PHP, and hands-on experience in using frameworks like Symfony, Spring Boot, Angular Fluent in English and French with a collaborative approach to problem-solving.

EDUCATION

HIGHER INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGICAL STUDIES OF SOUSSE

Sousse, TN

Bachelor's in Information Technology: Information Systems Development

Sep 2022 - Present

- Courses in software architectures, micro-services, collaborative work, and tools.
- Web development and software development with Python, Java, Flutter and PHP.
- Proficient in algorithms and projects management.

High School Rue Manzah Beni Khalled

Nabeul. TN

Bachelor of Computer Science

Sep 2021 – Jun 2022

EXPERIENCES

ITGATE GROUP Web Developer, Internship

Sousse, TN Jan 2024 – Feb 2024

- Developed user-friendly interfaces using Angular framework, enabling seamless manipulation of databases through REST APIs.
- Coded Backend solutions with Spring Boot Framework to enhance connection with MySQL databases thanks to JSON Documents.
- Dockerized multiple services and builded a multi-container application.

SNIT

El Manar II. TN Jan 2023 - Feb 2023

System Administration, Internship

- Assisted in various IT tasks, gaining practical experience in system management and technical
- Operated and dispatched new computers (10+) and IT equipments.
- Configured new accounts (email, Skype for Business) for 4 departments, facilitating communication for 40+ employees.
- Prepared new tools, including Skype for Business as a soft-phone and audio/video conferencing tools.
- Installed Office 365 and OneDrive, enhancing collaboration and productivity.

SKILLS

Technical Skills: Linux Administration, Linux, Shell scripting, Android, Symfony, Angular, React Flutter, Java, PHP, Python, C, , C++ SQL Databases, Git,

Soft Skills: Flexibility, Curiosity, Motivation, Team Work, Communication, Problem-solving, Googling

Languages: Fluent in French, English, Native in Arabic

ACTIVITIES AND LEADERSHIP

Google Developer Student Clubs

Sousse, TN Sep 2023 – Jun 2024

Design Core Team

- Collaborated on design projects to enhance the visual and user experience for club activities and initiatives.
- Contributed to branding and UI/UX design for club events, presentations, and social media content.